we've all been told it's important to
eat our vegetables what about drinking
our vegetables well green superfood
powder is also just called greens
powders have come a pretty long way in
the past few decades and now there's a
wide variety of these supplements for a
wide variety of purposes as well there
are supplements out there that are made
of a lot of ground up vegetables and sea
vegetables and fruits and Grains with
the goal of like improving anti-aging
like resilience to certain effects of
Aging also for vitamins for antioxidants
or probiotics for digestion all these
different categories and so today we are
going to be going through the best
greens powders on the market for your
individual needs I have tried out dozens
and dozens of green soup food powders to
land on this list for you guys and we're
going to be talking about not just the
best in each category but also the
science behind them the benefits of each
one the benefits of common ingredients
found them and we're answering very very
commonly asked questions especially the
most commonly asked question which is
can this just replace fruits and
vegetables
stick around to find out now before I go
on I should make a clear I'm not a
medical professional if you are making
big changes or any changes at all to
your supplement or nutrition regimen or
exercise regimen make absolutely
suddenly speak to a medical professional
who has knowledge of your history your
medications and this what's going to
work best for you and before answering a
couple questions about greens powders I
think I'm just going to tell you right
now what the best pick on the list is
because that's likely the way clicking
this video and I respect you so what I'm
going to show you here is athletic
greens ag1 this is a pick for the best
greens powder overall because very very
well rounded it's got a lot more
vitamins and minerals that you normally
see in Greens powders this also has a
ton of antioxidant dense ingredients
very very interesting products but I
also want to say
can you replace fruits and vegetables
with the greens powder no you cannot
don't do that if you're taking
multivitamin to get a lot of vitamins
and minerals greens powders are a very
interesting addition to your supplement
regimen as a means to supplement a bunch
of other healthful stuff that you'll
find in foods but just as the
multivitamins are not a replacement for
fruits and vegetables nor are these Nora
greens powders simply because there's a
lot more fiber in fruits and vegetables
and also typically more vitamins as well
check the nutrition labels you'll see
what I mean but greens powders are
interesting sources of antioxidants
phytonutrients and a lot of underserved
areas of nutrition that a lot of
supplements ignore now athletic greens
is our pick for the best green spotter
overall ag1 is the product I've got a
few other products as well the reason we
like ag1 is that it just is active in a
really wide area of nutrition this has a
lot of vitamins and minerals including a
lot of important ones especially if
you're not eating a ton of meat like
vitamin B12 you're also getting almost
500 of the regular daily intake of
vitamin C you're getting plenty of
biotin as well which a lot of people
like to take for stronger hand healthier
Nails healthier skin that kind of thing
but in addition to actual micronutrients
which again is pretty rare for these
sorts of nutrition supplements
surprisingly enough this has got a lot
of ingredients that are very very high
in antioxidants so ingredients like
wheatgrass spirulina chlorella these are
very very common in grease powder
because of the density of their
antioxidants but there's also more
they've got adaptogens which could help
the body to manage stress throughout the
day be that stress from a stressful day
the office or from a workout so
adaptogens have links to mental Clarity
and also work at recovery that kind of
thing on top of that you've got
probiotic bacteria which is going to be
good for the gut microbiome and the
bacteria that live in your gut that
helps you break down and digest food as
well as potentially have an impact on
inflammation and mental health and
Immunity all of that and there's
prebiotics in there as well and on top
of all of that it is surprisingly tasty
there are no artificial flavors or
sweetness or anything in this but
they've dropped in a couple of extracts
there's like some papaya powder in there
some mango powder so athletic greens
ag-1 definitely our favorite overall for
greens powders we also think ag1 is the
best greens powder for energy there's
such a wide variety of nutrients in
athletic greens there are a few
different ways it can help to
potentially improve energy levels so for
example there's alpha lipoic acid in
here which has a role in helping cells
convert glucose to energy there's also
CoQ10 which is a very interesting
supplement that has been found to
potentially help to increase the health
of the mitochondria of the cells which
is like where the energy is generated
inside our cells there's also a wide
range of adaptogens in here as I
mentioned earlier so stuff like
astragalus stuff like rhodiola rosea in
particular and a lot of people myself
included lexicod in the morning because
there's very interesting evidence and I
can speak from experience that it can
help to provide like a nice smooth
source of energy some clarity in a way
that caffeine doesn't so if you want to
get a bit more extra energy without
taking a whole bunch of extra caffeine a
lot of people have rodeola rosea as
their means for doing that so ag1 and
our favorite greens powder for energy
for a pretty wide variety of reasons
it's also our favorite greens powder for
digestion athletic greens has 7.2
billion probiotic bacteria per serving
and on top of that is from two different
families of bacteria because it's not
just the amount of bacteria in our guts
it's also the diversity of the
population that can play a key role in
improving various areas of our health
there's also some Prebiotic fiber in
here from inulin and other sources and
Prebiotic fiber feeds probiotic bacteria
so when you are combining the two of
them there's a lot of interesting
research suggesting that you kind of get
more out of the probiotics you consume
when you're also eating food for them to
eat which makes sense like the healthier
they spread to more areas of the
digestive tract and so on and then
lastly there are digestive enzymes in
here as well and there's been
interesting research suggesting that
taking enzymes helps to improve your
nutrient absorption and improve some
other areas of gut health as well so
you've got the probiotics you've got the
prebiotics and you get the digestive
enzymes and these are why ag1 is our
favorite greens fed up for digestion
before we move on from ag1 it is worth
knowing it is a bit on the pricey side
because there's just so much packed into
this product like more than other greens
powders in the market if you just get a
one-off bag and we just want to try it
out it's about 100 bucks for this bag of
30 servings so 50 cents per serving if
you subscribe though to get monthly
shipments so every 30 days after your 30
servings Runs Out you get a new bag the
price drops down to about two dollars
and sixty cents
next up we're going to talk about one of
our favorite supplement companies
offerings this is Wolverine Wolverine
has a greens and reds powder which we
find to be the best tasting on the
market when you see a Reds powder that
generally means they've added a bit more
fruits and berries into the mix than you
normally find because greens powders are
typically very very heavy on spirulina
and wheat grass like the really densely
green components this is a mix of the
two of them so you're getting
pomegranate juice powder in here
blueberry powder blueberry powder and so
on and what you're getting here is
something that is natural orange flavor
so no artificial flavors no artificial
sweeteners but unlike a lot of greens
powders Wolverine has gone ahead and
added flavoring to it to make it more
palatable and actually give it more of
like a flavor identity than you're gonna
find in other products we're a really
big fan of this one the natural orange
flavor and we also named it the best
greens powder for spirulina as well
spirulina maybe on par with wheat grass
as far as like the most popular
components in green superfood powders
it's really in a very very denseless of
antioxidants but there's also been a lot
of research on spirulina suggesting that
it can potentially help with
inflammation levels with immunity with
cholesterol with blood pressure a really
wide variety of them now in this product
you are getting two and a half grams of
Spirulina in every scoop but you're also
getting the same amount of wheatgrass
and chlorella so those three ingredients
chlorella wheatgrass and spirulina will
have pretty similar results in the
literature as far as like the
antioxidant density and the potential
effect on metabolic Health on the
waistline as well it's been some
interesting weight loss studies there
too obviously your calories the most
important feature nonetheless there is
pretty interesting evidence that adding
these very very antioxidant dense
components to your diet can have a very
wide ranging array of benefits so if you
want to get some of those benefits
Wolverines greens and reds is our
favorite vehicle for them and it's
pretty good tasting as well now before I
go on I know I am saying a lot of things
in a strange accent kind of quickly
about benefits and research and effects
and studies and literature uh so I would
understand if you would like a written
version of this article that goes into
more depth and has all these studies
that we have been citing throughout it
so we did that so if you want to Google
Barb and best greens powders the article
version of this video will come right up
and you can take in all this information
at your own pace and have a look at the
literature yourself and decide which of
these products is right for you so
definitely take a look at that article
and you will have a more comprehensive
and well-rounded approach this whole
area of nutrition and you'll be more
empowered to get the right product for
yourself
[Music]
so cost wise Wolverines is a lot less
expensive than ag1 at about 1.70 75
cents per serving but that is not the
best value greens powder on the market
the best greens powder for the money is
the option from costs Kos it's
pronounced cost this is our favorite
Christmas powder for the money it is
just one dollar per serving maybe like a
dollar and one cent but very inexpensive
for what you're getting here now it does
not have as broad an array of nutrients
and ingredients as the more pricey
option on the list naturally that makes
sense but it is still a good source of
ingredients that are high in
antioxidants so this one is not a
fantastic source of probiotics or
digestive enzymes do you have prebiotics
here the Prebiotic bacteria you get a
solid two grams of it and as mentioned
that's also still going to be a good
addition to your gut health on top of
that you're also getting these classic
antioxidant dense ingredients that you
find in Greens powders namely chlorella
spirulina wheatgrass and oat grass which
is also commonly in that family you're
not getting as much spirulina and
Chlorella getting 250 milligrams whereas
normally getting 2 500 milligrams of
those ingredients but you're also
getting a solid four gram serving of the
wheatgrass it comes in wheatgrass juice
powder wheatgrass whole powder and the
oat grass whole powder so that's still
that's a pretty impressive amount you're
definitely going to get a solid amount
of antioxidants there and their benefits
so Costas greens powder it doesn't have
like the probiotics and adaptogens are
some of the more expensive ones but it
is very dense in the classic most
coveted ingredients in these greens
powders like the the very dense greens
that we grow as chlorella or grass and
so on on top of that it has a nice Apple
sorbet flavoring so they put a bit more
effort into the flavoring than most
other greens powders and also weaning
this is our best pick for organic greens
powder they're often in Greens powders
you'll find some organic components but
they're not 100 organic so it doesn't
get that USDA organic certification and
you're not getting those potential
benefits of you know 100 organic
products that a lot of people like to
stick to especially the audience that
tends to like greens powders but right
here costs 100 organic they've got the
certification right there on the side
and every last one of the ingredients is
certified organic so if you say have
concerns about other kinds of pesticides
used in conventional farming and you
just want to stick to organic this is
going to be directly powder for you next
up while a lot of people like to get
plenty of grasses and seeds and so on in
their greens powders there are plenty
who want to emphasize the vegetable
content so that's why here we have the
best greens powders with the vegetable
blend and that one is here from gnarly
Sports Nutrition nope that's actually a
pre-workout
this is it this is the performance
greens from gnarly Sports Nutrition in
here you're going to be getting kale
spinach broccoli all the ones that your
mom tried to make eat when you were
younger and that you didn't want to or
ground up in here with a very nice
pleasant easy to stomach taste in
addition to that you got tomato not
technically a vegetable but still you do
find it on salad it's not in fruit
salads there's also kelp uh we got the
carrot too and you also have the normal
chlorella spirulina wheatgrass Oak grass
and barley grass so you have both the
classic Greenspan ingredients and the
ground up vegetables as well but it's
also a surprising nutritious greens
powder again while I think it's totally
fine to just expect the antioxidant
dense component and not really expect a
lot of vitamins and minerals this also
has the vitamins and minerals so you're
getting a really solid I'm talking about
100 of the recommended daily intake of
like vitamins a c e d k B12 great for
vegans vegetarians uh you're even
getting 12 of daily calcium in this one
so it's very nutritious with
micronutrients it's really nutritious as
far as the content of greens and
vegetables and you've also got
probiotics in this you've also got
adaptogens in the forms of cordyceps and
Rishi mushrooms and ginseng and you've
even got some organic beetroot here to
potentially improve nitric oxide blood
flow and sports performance very solid
product and we also think it's the best
creams powder on the go because they
also have a different version of this
where they all measured out into little
bags for daily servings you can buy a
bag of five and if you're traveling or
if you're just like out and about or if
you like to have this with a meal or
with lunch you can just take a mat on
the town with you so this is the best
with vegetables the best vegetable blend
greens powder and also the best greens
powder for folks on the go next up there
are some greens palettes out there that
are so high in fiber that you can
potentially use them to double as a
fiber supplement in addition to all the
other stuff that you're going to get in
degrees batter transparent Labs is our
favorite greens powder for fiber it's a
pretty easy argument to make this has
over 20 of the recommended daily intake
of fiber with six fat grams of it in
every serving what's interesting about
transparent Labs I we really like this
company here because they are very as
the name suggests it's transparent so if
you go to their site they'll typically
have like citations for why they include
all the ingredients they have this one
is very heavy on aquatic greens and
fiber that's what they're focusing on
they didn't go really hard on the
probiotics or on the ground up
vegetables or fruits that kind of stuff
they just kind of set for themselves
well look people tend to like spirulina
and chlorella so let's just use a lot of
that so there's six grams of the two of
them in this three grams of each which
is a very heavy in those two ingredients
in addition to that you have several
sources of fiber you got them from
Acacia fiber green banana Jerusalem
artichoke and chicory root and if you
are very familiar with the world of
nutrition then you may have noticed that
all those are sources of Prebiotic fiber
in addition to right you know regular
fiber like soluble and insoluble fiber
so what that is to say is not only is
this a good way to get over 20 21 of
your recommended intake of fiber you're
also getting a lot of Prebiotic fiber in
there which means that this as a source
of fiber is doesn't just have the normal
benefits of fiber it also has the gut
health benefits to your probiotic
bacteria that only Prebiotic fiber has
so transparent Labs have only one from a
greens powder is sea greens and fiber
then I recommend Prebiotic greens
aquatic greens and fiber they're just
like lean right into that direction and
they've made a very good wholly
dedicated greens powder in those two
areas speaking of greens and fiber
supplements if you're the type who likes
to combine your supplements be very
happy to know that there's a pretty
interesting entry in the list of greens
powders with proteins the supplement
that can combine the two of these hit
two beds one stone it's the really
gigantic bag in front of me from kylia
this is the best greens powder with
protein naturally this is bigger because
you're getting a lot more volume because
they have to fit in protein here what's
interesting as well is that it's vegan
protein so the forks who tend to
gravitate towards greens powders a good
percentage of those like to avoid you
know animal products at least where
possible so this one here it does have a
pretty considerable 11 grams of protein
in 126 calories but the protein itself
comes from a vegan blend of pea rice and
pumpkin seed so you're getting a pretty
good amount of protein here but also it
is indeed a dedicated greens powder like
you've got a ton of nutrition here
you've got like 100 of the daily vitamin
D you've got a 600 daily vitamin K which
a lot of us don't get enough of it helps
with bone strength especially when
you're taking calcium with it you've
also got choline like lutein about
antioxidants as well plenty of enzymes
getting five different enzymes here you
get a probiotics formulate here as well
from several different families you're
getting some adaptogens as well because
you're getting astragalusa root rhodiola
rosea all this kind of stuff so it is a
very good solid dedicated greens powder
they don't tell you how much probiotic
bacteria they have which is a little bit
annoying and also it is pretty pricey uh
it's 100 bucks for a bag so it's about
as much as athletic greens right you're
getting more calories and more protein
with it so it might see there's a probe
somebody there's a con it's not as dense
in some areas of the of the ingredients
as athletic greens is nonetheless you
are looking at about 3.33 cents per
serving if you subscribe to other price
drops to 85-ish Dollars and then you're
gonna be paying 2.80 cents per serving
so you do have options there subscribing
is always a good way to save some extra
money on your supplements you can do it
with Kaila and get living out of protein
with your greens lastly what's the best
screens powder for antioxidants you've
heard me say that word a lot in this
video and the thing with Dan Jackson's
is it's not hard to say and it's not
hard to find evidence that let's say
spirulina and chlorella are very high in
antioxidants very dense antioxins but
get really precise like how many
antioxidants or rather what is the
antioxidant potency of a product that's
a bit more complicated it's a bit harder
to do and very few companies go through
the trouble of getting it measured but
all right Energy Greens does orac is the
scale people use to measure the
antioxidant potency of a product it
stands for oxygen radical absorbance
capacity and this has an orac score of
40 000. now what that means is you're
getting about 10 times more antioxidants
than you're going to get in 100 grams of
blueberries which are pretty famously
dense in antioxidants so that's really
nice and probably if you've been
watching this video and you heard me say
that you experience a sense of relief
and satisfaction that you didn't realize
you were chasing when you were looking
at all the other products and that's
because they tell you precisely how
strong it is as far as antioxidant
potency goes on top of that there's also
like plenty of other ingredients as well
there are beta glucan mushrooms in here
which have interesting links with
lowering cholesterol as well you've got
plenty of organic berries you've got
probiotics and Prebiotic bacteria in
here and then the probiotics you're
getting 1.2 billion which is not as many
as athletic greens but it still is
pretty considerable and you get them
from about a half dozen different
families so that's really nice for the
diversity of the gut there's more in
here there's plenty of adaptogens
there's plenty of uh Ginger extracts and
other ingredients designed to lower
inflammation it's a very solid greens
powder it is not as tasty as the other
products here but it is not as
disgusting as I would say the majority
of brings palettes out there and it's
and it's pretty inexpensive too this tub
here is about a dollar per day and if
you get a bigger one of uh 60 servings
the price drops to about 70 cents per
serving so very inexpensive very
transparent with how strong and how
effective it is and you're also getting
plenty of other stuff outside of uh
simply greens and antioxidants with the
adapters and everything like that so
yeah very very solid pick from orac
energy greens so that does it for our
list of the best greens powders I wanted
to just quickly go over again the
difference in Greens powders and
multivitamins as a question that we get
a lot to summarize what I said earlier
in this video multivitamins provide
vitamins and minerals sometimes other
stuff but generally vitamins and
minerals together and the FDA has
official recommendations for the daily
intake of vitamins and minerals then
there's other areas of nutrition
specifically like antioxidants and we'll
talk about a lot antioxidants and
phytonutrients that are in some respects
they're vitamins that didn't make the
cut like that haven't been deemed as
necessary as the uh the essential
vitamins and minerals however when you
hear every other day that a study has
come out saying that you know
blueberries have this lentil longevity
or this kind of fruit has that linked to
a less prostate cancer and that sort of
thing this is usually studies on
antioxidants and phytonutrients that
have been found to be linked to certain
benefits so it's a really good idea to
get a lot of antioxidants and
phytonutrients and just so you know what
I mean with this word I've been saying
over and over again in this video
antioxidants help to combat the damage
that occurs the cells in our bodies from
free radicals so long story short
antioxidants help to slow or prevent
cellular damage and in that respect they
actually help to slow certain effects of
Aging which is very exciting to a lot of
people and that's why a lot of people
like to get their antioxidants in the
diet outside of those again you've got
the adaptogens helping the body to
manage stress they can also provide some
nice Natural Energy and improve focus
they've also got probiotics and
prebiotics and enzymes to help improve
Digestive Health as well now varying
products in the industry have other
things in them but those are broadly the
areas of nutrition that antioxidants
provide and when you get asked that
question again and Jackson's versus
multivitamins what's the difference
antioxidants exists to provide nutrition
in areas that multivitamins don't and
there are actually a lot of areas of
nutrition outside of vitamins and
minerals although officially according
to the FDA but with minerals those are
the most important parts of nutrition
there's a lot more that you should be
looking out too so that's all I've got
for you today if you want to check out
the written version of this article and
so you can go through this at your own
pace again you can Google it bar Bend
best greens powders it'll come right up
and I hope to see you for the next video
[Music]
thank you